Yashwant Kumar Singh

Graduate Computer Engineer

 $13^{\rm th}$ Main Street, Singhshandra, Bangalore, INDIA 560068 | (91) 7002169604 | yashwantkrsingh1997@gmail.com | LinkedIn Github7

Profile

Friendly and engaging team player and able to inspire staff to perform their best. I'm a fast learner programmer and strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology in computer science and engineering from India. I love building Android applications and contributing to my open source projects. Currently learning more about networking, flutter and backend. All the projects I have worked on can be found on GitHub platform. I also like to answer questions on Stack overflow platform during my free time.

Experience

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER | LUNATIC GAMES | SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

- implemented software developments and changes, implementing new features to my existing GitHub Repo projects
- · working on a web3 application.
- · hands on React framework

ASSOCIATE ANDROID DEVELOPER |GLOIFY, BANGALORE | AUGUST 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2022

- · Worked as Associate android developer.
- Implementation of track selection allows users to select video quality manually, basically redo of Hls Player (HLS player repo) The application uses Exo-player library. Exo-player version used 2.14.0.
- · Started implementing Kotlin.
- · Started implementing full life-cycle android development.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | COMPUTER SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS LLC, KOLKATA| NOVEMBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022

- · Worked as an intern.
- · Tested and contributed new features applications with superiors (java).
- · Started implementing different features (fragment, recycle view, spinner, and banner).
- · Worked on how to use swaggerAPI call [create, delete].
- · Learned about crashlytics, how to push merge request implementation.

PLACID VISION PVT LTD, BANGALORE | OCTOBER 2018 - AUGUST 2019

- · Worked as an intern.
- · Developed application for android phone/ android tv.
- · Alongside college years, developed and Tested new android software applications with superiors (java).
- · Hands on Linux, ffmpeg library, LAMP.
- worked on streaming media, live video streaming to different devices(Android, YouTube, Facebook, Sites, etc).

 Worked alongside team members to investigate software solutions, provided technical support when necessary

Education

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

| JUNE 2022 |

Dayananda Sagar College of Engineering, Bangalore, India

HIGH SCHOOL

| JUNE 2017 |

Nps International School, Guwahati Assam, India

Skills & Abilities

- programming c++,Java, Linux bash script,javascript,next.js ,react application,web3.
- · operating system Linux, windows
- · database MySQL
- management skills critical thinking, time management, problem-solving, fast learner, effective communication and presentation
- **GitHub** create merge request, create issues
- · Android studio android app development
- · firebase- login Api authentication
- · LINUX APACHE MYSQL
- Exoplayer play live streaming video on demand, users can manually control video quality.
- ffmpeg live video encoding & decoding [hls,m3u8,h265,h264,av1],live video streaming using rtsp ,http protocol

Activities and Interests

Theater, environmental conservation, hiking, swimming, travel, gaming, workout, soccer.